Joyce (Xiaoxia) Ding

Summary

Enthusiastic IT programming student with a passion for data and experience in public relations and project management. Particularly interested in Machine Learning and healthcare-focused web/mobile app development.

Skills

Front-End & Frameworks: JavaScript, Bootstrap, React JS, HTML, CSS, ASP.net

Back-End & Databases: SQL, ExpressJS, NodeJS, C#, Java, Python, C++, C

Cloud Services & Al: Azure, Transformer, Microsoft ML Model

Non-Technical Skills: Communication, Collaboration, Leadership, Time Management

Education

Diploma in IT Programming Nova Scotia Community College Bachelor's in Construction Management Chongqing University

Graduated 2002

Expected Graduation: June 2024

Work and Industry Experience

NSCC Blackbird SPR Project | Halifax, NS

April 2023 to May 2023

System Operator

- Developed a Web application Student Progress Record to help faculty manage student's academic progress.
- · Used asp.net MVVM architecture and C# in a team of 10 persons under Scrum frameworks.
- · Managed project's Github repository and configured SendGrid API in the program to fulfill the functionality of confirming and resetting passwords.

Weber Shandwick, IPG Group | Guangzhou, China

May 2010 to April 2014

Account Director

- · Led PR strategy and execution for clients including Microsoft and Nike.
- · Built websites, designed mobile games, and managed social media platforms for various clients.

Burson-Marsteller, WPP Group | China

July 2005 to September.2008

Associate

 Managed media relations, prepared media material, and provided crisis training for tech clients included Intel, HP, SAP and 3LCD.

Industry and Personal Projects

Ultimate Airmate Bicycle Contest

January 2012 to April 2014

Account Director Weber Shandwick

· Led national projects promoting energy efficiency and environmental awareness.

Toastmaster Ah Counter Web Application

August 2023

Developer

· Self-taught and built web application for tracking speech analytics.

Extra-Curricular and Volunteer Activities

Atlantic Toastmaster SMU | Halifax, NS

June 2023 to Present

Member

· Attend weekly meeting to improve public speaking and leadership skills.

itjobfair.ca NSCC | Halifax, NS

November 2022 to March 2023

Volunteer Tech Team

· Instructed and prepared tutorial video for industry members to set up team channels.

Qileyuan Autonomic Community | Guangzhou, China

2012 to 2021

Initiator, Organizer, Volunteer

- Initiated and organized a successful community initiative in China.
- Community residents pay \$0.2 m²/month and can enjoy community facilities and services worth \$2m²/month.

Awards and Certifications

Google Data Analytic Certificate, Coursera and Google

August 2022

First Place - NSCC Challenge Nova Scotia

November 2023

(As Project Manager and Team lead)

 Interbrand Best China Brands, PRWeek Honourable Mention (As Project Manager and Team lead) 2013

Language

· English IELTS 7.0 | Native Mandarin and Cantonese | French learner